Indiana University Department of Folklore and Ethnomusicology records, 1942-2010 C383
Indiana University Archives
- Folklore Institute, 1942-2007 (Box 1)
  - Individual subject files, 1965-2007 (Box 14)
    - Grimshaw, Polly - Library Folklore, 1978 (Box 15)
    - Gunn, Giles, 1979 (Box 15)
    - Halpert, Herbert, 1970-2001 (Box 15)
    - Hamer, Lynn, 1993 (Box 15)
    - Hand, Wayland D., 1970-1981 (Box 15)
    - Haque, A.S.M. Zahurul, 1988 (Box 15)
    - Hasse, John, 1979-1998 (Box 15)
    - Helton, Sally, 1980-1981 (Box 15)
    - Hocker, Tom, 1984 (Box 15)
    - Hofer, Tamas, 1988 (Box 15)
    - Holbek, Bengt, 1983 (Box 15)
    - Honko, Lauri, 1983-2002 (Box 15)
    - Horne, Ron, 1991 (Box 15)
    - Hufford, David J., 1984 (Box 15)
    - Hummings, Amadi, 1992 (Box 15)
    - Hummings, Amadi - Viola, 1992 (Box 15)
    - Humphrey, Linda - Tufts Citrus Community College, 1978-1980 (Box 15)
    - Humphrey, Theodore - Cal. State Polytechnic University, 1978-1980 (Box 15)
    - Huseby, Eva "Women as Agents of Continuity, 1986 (Box 15)
    - Indiana Historical Society, 1980-1996 (Box 15)
    - Inta's Workshop - Potential Fieldwork Funding Sources, 1987 (Box 15)
    - International Research and Exchanges Board - Correspondence - H-A Grand, 1984-1989 (Box 15)
    - Islam, Mazharul, 1971-1981 (Box 15)
    - Ives, Edward D., 1973-1984 (Box 15)
    - Ivey, William and Saundra, 1973-1999 (Box 15)
    - Jackson, Bruce, 1971-1981 (Box 15)
    - Janelli, Roger, 1979-1981 (Box 15)
    - Jansen, William, 1969-1979 (Box 15)
    - Jasiak, Michael - IU, Kokomo TV, 1991 (Box 15)
    - Johnson, Cindy - Paper Rec, Student Paper Committee, 1988 (Box 15)
    - Jones, Michael O., 1974-1980 (Box 15)
    - Jubbour, Alan, 1976-1985 (Box 15)
    - Kanellos, Nick, February 1981 (Box 15)
    - Kaufman, Debra, 1981 (Box 15)
    - Kawthekar, P. N., 1980 (Box 15)
    - Kennedy, Meg, 1981 (Box 15)
    - Kern, Jackson, 1996 (Box 15)
    - Ketcham, Carl, 1979 (Box 15)
    - Kim, Sun Pong, 1981-1986 (Box 15)
    - Kirk, Russell, 1979-1980 (Box 16)
    - Kirshenblatt-Gimblett, Barbara, 1973-1981 (Box 16)
    - Klein, Barbro, 1971-1981 (Box 16)
    - Klymasz, Robert, 1980, 1982 (Box 16)
    - Knecht, Peter, 1980-1982 (Box 16)
    - Lane, James - IFOH [Indiana Folklore/Oral History] - IUNW [IU Northwest] Campus Gary M., 1988 (Box 16)
    - Langlois, Janet, 1978-1987 (Box 16)
    - Lawless, Elaine, 1980-1981 (Box 16)
    - Leary, Jim, 1990-1992 (Box 16)
    - Lehtipuro, Outi, 1993 (Box 16)
    - Levine, Lawrence, 1976-1979 (Box 16)
    - Levine, Stuart, 1978 (Box 16)
    - Lewis, Mrs. A., 1992 (Box 16)
    - Lewis, Mary Ellen - Tenure File, 1977-1979 (Box 16)
    - Lewis, Vincent, 1993 (Box 16)
    - Life History as Cultural Construction Performance by Barbara K-G (Budapest), 1987 (Box 16)
    - Lindahl, Carl, 1978-1979 (Box 16)
    - Lipson-Walker, Carolyn, 1978-1981 (Box 16)
    - Lison-Tolosana, Carmelo, 1978 (Box 16)
    - List, George, 1978-1983 (Box 16)
    - Lloyd, Tim, 1978-1991 (Box 16)
    - Lockwood, William and Yvonne, 1972-1980 (Box 16)
    - Loomis, Ormond H. - Florida Folklore, 1980-1986 (Box 16)
    - Louis, Pamela - Kansas City, Kansas Community College, 1978-1980 (Box 16)
    - Lowe, H.I.C., 1979 (Box 16)
    - Lowney, Jim, 1980 (Box 16)
    - MacDonald, Margaret, 1978 (Box 16)
    - Mackesy, Eileen M. - MLA [Modern Language Association]: data base for research-in-progress, 1987, 1995 (Box 16)
    - MacLaughlin, Jean, 1979-1982 (Box 16)
    - Mailing Lists: Misc., 1979-2001 (Box 16)
    - Manley, Kathleen, 1994 (Box 16)
    - Manuel E. Arsenio - Folktales of the Philippines, 1983 (Box 16)
    - March, Richard, 1978-1981 (Box 16)
    - Marshall, Howard, 1978-1981 (Box 16)
    - Mason, Evelyn, 1983 (Box 16)
    - McDonald, James, 1983 (Box 16)
    - McDowell, John, 1979-1995 (Box 16)
    - McGowan, Thomas, 1981 (Box 16)
    - McLaughlin, Ann Louise - Harvard University Press, 1977-1978 (Box 16)
    - McMahon, David F. - St. Francis College, 1978-1980 (Box 16)
    - McNeil, William K., 1978-1981 (Box 16)
    - Mechling, Jay, 1978 (Box 16)
    - Meyer, Richard E. - Oregon College of Education, 1978-1982 (Box 16)
    - Messenger, John E., 1974-1981 (Box 16)
    - Mieder, Wolfgang, 1974-1980 (Box 16)
    - Miller, Wayne D., 1979, 1982 (Box 16)
    - Milspaw, Yvonne, 1977 (Box 16)
    - Misc. Students, 1996 (Box 16)
    - Mitchell, Roger, 1970-1975 (Box 16)
    - Mink, Charles R. - Lincoln University, 1978 (Box 16)
    - Moe, John F., 1979-1980 (Box 16)
    - Montenyohl, Eric, 1982, 1988 (Box 16)
    - Montell, Lynwood, 1971-1988 (Box 16)
    - Moore, Willard B., 1978-1982 (Box 16)
    - Mueller, Franz H., 1982 (Box 16)
    - Najam, Ted, 1981-1982 (Box 16)
    - Prof Yi Namsik - Andong University, 1991 (Box 16)
    - National Humanities Center, 1977-1980 (Box 16)
    - Nelson, John B., 1984 (Box 16)
    - Newall, Venetia, 1971-1981 (Box 16)
    - Nicolaisen, W.F.H., 1973-1981 (Box 16)
    - Ninomiya, Testsuo, 1980-1983 (Box 16)
    - Norkuvas, Martha Lowell Videotape Project, 1983 (Box 16)
    - Norris, Sabobu, 1992 (Box 16)
    - Noy, Dov, 1972-1985 (Box 16)
    - Ofield, Jack, Bowling Green Films, Inc., 1980-1981 (Box 16)
    - Oinas, Felix, 1978-1981 (Box 16)
    - Ohrn, Steve, 1989, 1992 (Box 16)
    - Olabimtan, Afolabi, 1983-1984 (Box 16)
    - Opland, Jeff, 1981-1982 (Box 16)
    - Oring, Elliott, 1975-1988 (Box 16)
    - Osterhoudt, Bill A-C-D [Auburn, Cord, Duesenberg], 1985 (Box 16)
    - Paredas, Americo, 1970-1979 (Box 16)
    - Pattanayak, D.P., 1978-1979 (Box 16)
    - Pearson Ronald, 1992 (Box 16)
    - Pitchford, Christopher, undated (Box 16)
    - Ponder Document, April 20, 1990 (Box 16)
    - Ponder, Samuel, Folklore, 1989 (Box 17)
    - Raben, Johnson Paradigm Press, Archives project, 1987 (Box 17)
    - Rao, Panduranga, 1983 (Box 17)
    - Reed, Alice - Book Corral Southwest State University, 1981-1982 (Box 17)
    - Regan, Arthur E. - San Jose State University, 1978-1981 (Box 17)
    - Reuss, Richard, 1970-2001 (Box 17)
    - Ribeiro, Immanuel - Independent F800, 1990-1991 (Box 17)
    - Ridlen, Susan, 1980 (Box 17)
    - Rikoon, Sandy, 1979-1990 (Box 17)
    - Ristine, Richard O., 1980-1982 (Box 17)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1978-1981 (Box 17)
    - Rosenberg, Bruce A., 1976-1992 (Box 17)
    - Rosenberg, Neil, 1973-1980 (Box 17)
    - Ross, Susie Balliet, 1982 (Box 17)
    - Roth, Klaus, 1986-1987 (Box 17)
    - Rudjak, Joseph S., 1981 (Box 17)
    - Rueter, Rebecca C., 1981-1982 (Box 17)
    - Rumer, Tom, 1978 (Box 17)
    - Ryan, President John W., 1979-1986 (Box 17)
    - Rushforth, Sam, 1997 (Box 17)
    - Sacket, S. J., 1973-1979 (Box 17)
    - Safier, Gwendolyn, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Sailes, Gary, 1990 (Box 17)
    - Samuelson, Sue, 1984 (Box 17)
    - Santino, Jack, 1979-1981 (Box 17)
    - Sarkany, Mihaly, 1988 (Box 17)
    - Seward, Adrienne L., 1979 (Box 17)
    - Shipps, Jan 1980, 1983 (Box 17)
    - Shoupe, Catherine, 1979-1980 (Box 17)
    - Shusterman, Alan, 1979-1981 (Box 17)
    - Siefert, Marsha, 1978-1980 (Box 17)
    - Skaggs Foundation, 1983-1988 (Box 17)
    - Singh, M. Sansa, 1988-1989 (Box 17)
    - Smith, Larry W (Honey Creek film) 6-14-84, 1984 (Box 17)
    - Staub, Shalom, 1992-1993 (Box 17)
    - Stekert, Ellen J., 1973-1976 (Box 17)
    - Slater, Candace, 1981-1982 (Box 17)
    - Steiner, Margie, 1988 (Box 17)
    - Stein, Mary Beth, 1988 (Box 17)
    - Stern, Steve, 1980-1989 (Box 17)
    - Stewart, Romericus, 1990 (Box 17)
    - Stillwell, Ruth Messenger, 1983 (Box 17)
    - Stone, Ruth, 1979-1989 (Box 17)
    - Suarez, Axania, 1992 (Box 17)
    - Sullivan, Wallace, Outdoor Museum, 1976 (Box 17)
    - Taegon, Kim, 1980-1981 (Box 17)
    - Tax, Sol, 1972, 1978 (Box 17)
    - Teaching Folklore in Language and Literature Symposium - B.J. Stoeltje, 1994-1995 (Box 17)
    - Thigpen, Kenneth, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Thill, Richard S., 1978-1979 (Box 17)
    - Toelken, Barre, 1972-1983 (Box 17)
    - Tokofsky, Peter, 1988 (Box 17)
    - University of Illinois Press, undated (Box 17)
    - Vaughn, Kathryn, 1990 (Box 17)
    - Vellani, Annal - Ford Foundation, 1988 (Box 17)
    - Vidal, A. O., 1982-1985 (Box 17)
    - Vidutis, Richard, 1979-1980 (Box 17)
    - Vlach, John Michael, 1974, 1981 (Box 17)
    - Voorheis, Peter, 1981-1982 (Box 17)
    - Wachs, Eleanor, 1979-1981 (Box 17)
    - Walker, Dean, 1993 (Box 17)
    - Walker, Tom, 1999-2000 (Box 17)
    - Ward, Donald, 1974, 1980 (Box 17)
    - Warshaver, Gerald, 1976, 1978 (Box 17)
    - Wartenberg, Dorothy, NEH Summer Seminar, 1980 (Box 17)
    - Washburn, Wilcomb, 1978-1979 (Box 17)
    - Watson, Carla, 1981 (Box 17)
    - Weber, Daniel, 1991 (Box 17)
    - Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthro Research, 1978, 1980 (Box 17)
    - White, John, 1991 (Box 17)
    - Wiegman, Nancy, 1975-1980 (Box 17)
    - Wiegman, Neal, 1969-1980 (Box 17)
    - Wildhaber, Robert, Folktales of Switzerland, 1971-1980 (Box 17)
    - Wilgus, D.K., 1970-1974 (Box 17)
    - Williams, Jack, 1979-1986 (Box 17)
    - Williams, Reva, 1990-1992 (Box 17)
    - Wilson, George, 1976-1979 (Box 17)
    - Wilson, A. William, 1979-1998 (Box 17)
    - Winninger, John, 1988 (Box 17)
    - Witswatersrand University Press Mrs. N H Wilson, Head, 1986-1988 (Box 17)
    - Yeboa-Dankwa, Prof. University of Ghana, 1989 (Box 17)
    - Yerkovich, Sally, 1979-1982 (Box 17)
    - Yoels, William C. Indiana University Northwest, 1978-1980 (Box 17)
    - Zimmerman, Zora D., 1978-1981 (Box 17)
    - Zoltan, Fejos, 1990 (Box 17)
- Ethnomusicology Institute, 1973-2008 (Box 5)
  - Administrator/Project Coordinator in the Archives of African American Music, 2007 (Box 18)
  - Alan P. Merriam, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Archives of Traditional Music (ATM) (Box 5)
    - Search, Associate Director, 1985-1986 (Box 18)
    - Advisory, 1981-1988 (Box 5)
    - Catalog of African Music and Oral Data Holdings, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Catalog of Latin American Recordings of Music and the Spoken Word, 1968 (Box 5)
  - Dietrick Schuller, "Field Recording and Sound Archiving at the Turn to Digital Age", 1990 (Box 5)
  - Ethnomusicology (Box 5)
    - Administrative Files, Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, Programs, etc., 1986-1987 (Box 5)
    - Brochure, 1977-1979 (Box 5)
    - Conference, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 5)
    - Courses, 1984-1985 (Box 5)
    - Curriculum – Folklore/Anthropology/Afro-American Studies, 1970-1979 (Box 5)
    - Department Newsletter, December 1983 (Box 5)
    - Faculty Meetings, 1979-1984 (Box 5)
    - General, undated (Box 5)
    - Hiring Docs, 2008 (Box 18)
    - Minors Students, 1979-1985 (Box 18)
    - Pos., 1978-1979 (Box 5)
    - Program, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
    - Program, 1982-1984; (2 folders) (Box 18)
  - Program Circular, 1973-1983 (Box 18)
  - Program Student Interviews, 1982-1983 (Box 18)
  - Publications Group Financial Information, 1983-1985 (Box 5)
  - Reorganization 1980, Folklore, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Student Association, Silver Anniversary for the Society of Ethnomusicology, Response to the Freezing of the Position of Head of the Archives of Traditional Music, 1979-1981 (Box 5)
  - Student Info, Faculty Service, Correspondence, 1980-1985 (Box 18)
  - Student List, 1984-1985 (Box 18)
  - Students, 1977-1986; (2 folders) (Box 18)
  - Folklore Courses F516/F517/F512, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Korean Festival/Masks, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Latin Studies/African Studies, 1980-1985 (Box 5)
  - Letter concerning Ethnomusicology Students from the Director of the Archives of Traditional Music to the Ethnomusicology Faculty, March 9, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Meeting Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Plans, 1978-1983 (Box 5)
  - Service, 1984-1985 (Box 5)
  - Service-Professional Activities, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Society for Ethnomusicology (Box 5)
    - 1974-1981 (Box 5)
    - Meeting, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Meeting, University of Mississippi, October 1993 (Box 5)
    - R. Smith Conference Notes, 1980 (Box 5)
    - 50th Anniversary Meeting, 2005 (Box 5)
  - Student Information/Course Description, 1984 (Box 18)
  - Syllabi (Ruth Stone), 1977-1982 (Box 5)
- Special Projects, 1944-2010 (Box 5)
  - General Projects Files, 1944-2010 (Box 5)
    - Archives of African American Music and Culture (AAAMC), 2006-2007 (Box 5)
    - Academic Writing: 31 Points, 1977 (Box 5)
    - American Folklore Society (AFS) Indiana Breakfast, 1981 (Box 5)
    - Archive Slide Project, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Archives of Traditional Music (ATM), 2005-2008 (Box 5)
      Separated Material
      One floppy disk has been removed for preservation purposes. For more information, please contact Indiana University Archives staff.
    - Award Letters and Due Dates for Reports NEH National Endowment for the Humanities, 1985 (Box 5)
    - Brunvand Finds New "Urban Legends" Keep Cropping Up, May 20, 1990 (Box 5)
    - Center for Southern Folklore Newsletter, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
    - Computer Correspondence, 1986 (Box 6)
    - Computer Proposal Document, 1987 (Box 6)
    - Computing Services, 1982-1984 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, Ensemble Instruments, 2007 (Box 6)
    - Dissertation Application for RM Dorson Award in Fieldwork, 1988-1989 (Box 18)
    - Dorson, Richard M. (Box 6)
    - Award Applicants, 1980-1991; (9 folders) (Box 6)
    - Dissertation Award, 1984-1986 (Box 18)
    - Fieldwork Award (original applications), 1987-1988 (Box 18)
    - Prize, 1988 (Box 18)
    - Outstanding Paper in Folklore Submission, 1988 (Box 18)
    - Award Letters, 1990-1991; (7 folders) (Box 6)
    - Edson Richmond, 1961-1973 (Box 6)
    - Folklore Archives Planning Group (contains a 1991 Report on the State of the Folklore Archives), 1982-1991 (Box 6)
    - Folklore Computer Phase II, 1988-1996 (Box 6)
    - Folklore Forum, Special Series no. 8, Papers on Applied Folklore, 1971 (Box 6)
    - Folklore Institute Reorganization, 1980-1984 (Box 6)
    - Foxfire Outreach, 1992 (Box 6)
    - Fulbright Fellowship Interviews, October 1993 (Box 18)
    - General Proposal for a Videotape Laboratory and Viewing Station at the Indiana University Archives of Traditional Music, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Ghost Walk, correspondence (Box 6)
      - October 2003 (Box 6)
      - October 2004 (Box 6)
      - 2005 (Box 6)
    - Gros Louis, Kenneth R. R. – Vice President, 1976-1981 (Box 6)
    - Hoosier Folklore Society, 1980-1982 (Box 6)
    - Indiana Folk Arts Survey Forms, 1998 (Box 6)
    - Inta's Correspondence, 1993-2006 (Box 18)
    - IU Outdoor Museum of Folklife, 1968-1974 (Box 6)
    - Journal: Clifty Falls State Park Folk Art Project, Nancy A Cassell, Summer 1980 (Box 6)
    - Lawrence W. Levine, Black Culture and Black Conciousness: African-American Folk Thought from Slavery to Freedom – Notes, undated (Box 6)
    - Letter concerning the selection of "The Classics Come Home" and "Joy Unspeakable" for a series marketed to public broadcasting, 1986 (Box 6)
    - Liberian Collection, 2005-2007 (Box 6)
    - Linda Dégh's Projects, 1991-1993 (Box 6)
    - List of Woodblocks from the Indiana University Archives, July 4, 2010 (Box 6)
    - Mariachi, 2005 (Box 6)
    - Memos to Edson, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Memorial Letters to Contributors - Dorson (Box 6)
      - A-L, 1982-1987 (Box 6)
      - M-Z, 1983-1985 (Box 6)
    - Mud Paintings – accompanying materials, 1978-1987 (Box 6)
    - More of Tina Bucuvalas' Greek material – Greek Traditional Arts Project, 1984-1986 (Box 6)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, Indiana Co-Fairs, 2002-2003 (Box 6)
    - National Research Council (NRC) Program Questionnaire, 2006-2007 (Box 6)
    - Negro Folklore, undated (Box 6)
    - National Endowment of the Humanities, Indy I: Proposal, 1978-1979 (Box 6)
    - National Research Council Program Questionnaire, 2006 (Box 6)
    - Ongoing Activities: Folklore Archives 2000s, 2004-2009 (Box 6)
    - Ongoing Projects: Richard M. Dorson Library, 1986-1987 (Box 6)
    - Project Photographs (Box 6)
      - Quilts, undated (Box 6)
      - Undated (moved to Archives photograph collection) (Box 6)
      - Water Witching, December 14, 1987 (Box 6)
    - Projects: Arabic Tale Type Index, 1983 (Box 6)
    - Projects: Archives Computerized Index (NEH), 1980-1982 (Box 6)
    - Projects: US Constitution (unfunded), 1983 (Box 6)
    - Projects: Folklore at Indiana U. (Skaggs), 1985 (Box 6)
    - Projects: Folkways, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
    - Project: MLA (Modern Language Association) (Box 6)
      - 1988-1993 (Box 6)
      - Bibliography, 1989-1991 (Box 7)
    - Projects, Motif Index Computerization, Joy, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Projects: Preparation of Future Faculty (IU – Not Funded), 1995-1996 (Box 7)
    - Public Folk Cultural Programs: A Survey and Products Listing, March 1989 (Box 7)
    - Publicity, 1979-1998 (Box 7)
    - Question File Correspondence, Gale Research Co., 1978 (Box 7)
    - Richmond, Edson - Vita, 1944-1981 (Box 7)
    - Richmond's Correspondence, 1981-1986 (Box 18)
    - Special Projects Committee Activities, 1986-2002 (Box 7)
    - Special Projects Unit: Mission Statement, 1983 (Box 7)
    - SPMS-80s-001 (Box 7)
      - Belanus – Teacher's Workshop/Book, 1984 (Box 7)
      - Bustin Project: Indiana Social History, 1984; (2 folders) (Box 7)
      - White River Park Humanities Project, 1982 (Box 7)
    - Sound and Video Analysis and Instruction Laboratory, SAVAIL, 2001-2003 (Box 7)
    - South Carolina: McKissick Museum, Folklife and Education Institute, 1994 (Box 7)
    - Traditional Arts Indiana (TAI) (Box 7)
      - 2001-2004 (Box 7)
      - 2003-2004 (Box 7)
      - Advisory Board, 1999 (Box 7)
      - General, 1998-2002 (Box 7)
      - Search Committee, 2004 (Box 18)
      - Indiana State Fair, 2004 (Box 7)
  - Public Initiatives, 1967-2007 (Box 7)
    - Branches of History by Donna Ray, Monroe County Community School Corporation, 1984 (Box 7)
    - Carpenter-Stafford Collaborative Visions of Place, 1995-1998 (Box 7)
    - Carpenter-Stafford Collaboration (Box 7)
      - Common Ground, 1999 (Box 7)
      - Crestmont NEA, 2005-2007 (Box 7)
      - Memory in Place Conf., 2006 (Box 7)
        One DVD has been removed for preservation purposes. For more information, please contact Indiana University Archives staff.
      - Museum of the Person – Indiana, 2000-2005 (Box 7)
    - Changing Times in Monroe County: Lifestyles as Experienced by the People of Monroe County During the 20th Century – Oral History Research Project – Victor and Virginia Dixon, 1979 (Box 7)
    - Cassette Tape #26, July 17, 1979 - Victor and Virginia Dixon, Interviewer: Carol Darling, MCCSC Oral History Research Project (Box 7)
      Scope and Content Note
      Oral history inteview with Victor and Virginia Dixon on their memories of life in Bloomington during both World Wars and beyond. They describe Bloomington neighborhoods and their history dating back to the Underground Railroad, race relations, segregation, housing development, small businesses, poverty during the Great Depression, schoolhouses and childhood games, serving in the miltary, work opportunities, gender, and parenting.
    - Coalition for Educational Schools, 1994 (Box 13)
    - Connecticut: Institute for Community Research, 1994 (Box 7)
    - Education: Ruby Rufty "Elementary School, 1978 (Box 7)
    - Educational Testing Services, 1994 (Box 7)
    - F803 Common Ground Cassette Tapes (Box 13)
      - Common Ground Interview – Copy of MCHS 99-02 & 03 Russel Shaw, circa 1996-1999 (Box 13)
        Interview with Russel Shaw on his historic photography collection of downtown Bloomington and his experiences as a small business owner of a photography shop on Kirkwood Avenue. He shares reflections on Bloomington during World War II, union protests, early recycling programs, and celebrating national holidays with his family.
      - Common Ground: Anya Royce Discussion, Tape 1, June 10, 1996 (Box 13)
        The first of several weekly meetings in 1996 between Indiana University Folklore and Ethnomusicology graduate students involved in the Common Grounds project, featuring Dr. Anya Royce. Discussion on relationships in fieldwork, embodied knowledge, service learning, race relations, working with children and seniors, and volunteering Bloomington, IN.
      - Common Ground: Anya Royce Discussion, Tape 2, June 10, 1996 (Box 13)
        Continued discussion on volunteering in Bloomington, IN, individual and team fieldwork, educational relationships and institutional change, fieldwork with racial minorities and children, and fiedlwork in Martinsville, IN
      - Common Groud: Phil Stafford Discussion, June 24, 1996 (Box 13)
        The second of several weekly meetings in 1996 between Indiana University Folklore and Ethnomusicology graduate students involved in the Common Grounds project, featuring Dr. Henry Glassie and Phil Stafford of the Evergreen Applied Folklore Project. Discussion on inter-generational applied folkore at the Evergreen Nursing Home and the Harmony School focused on notions of place, linking folklore to public policy and affordable housing development in Bloomington, IN.
      - Common Ground: Teamwork Discussion (following Phil Stafford), June 24, 1996 (Box 13)
        Continued conversation between Glassie and folkore and ethnomusicology graduate students immediately following their conversation with Phil Stafford. Discussion on the team's project plan to develop programming between children's and seniors' communities in Bloomington, contemplating the relationships between fieldwork, teamwork, and volunteering.
      - Common Ground: Team Scheduling Discussion, July 1, 1996 (Box 13)
        Third of several weekly meetings between folklore and ethnomusicology graduate students. Discussion on scheduling and reflections on topics raised in public folklore readings and films.
      - Common Ground: "Teams" Discussion, July 8, 1996 (Box 13)
        Fourth of several weekly meetings between folklore and ethnomusicology graduate students. Discussion on theories of teamwork and leadership, as well as planning for public folklore programming in Bloomington.
      - Common Ground Discussion: Glassie 7, Tape 1, July 22, 1996 (Box 13)
        Dr. Henry Glassie joins the team to discuss ethical fieldwork, problems of scale, relationships with informants and the community, applied folklore in Bloomington, and service learning.
      - Common Ground Discussion: Glassie 7, Tape 2, July 22, 1996 (Box 13)
        Glassie concludes the conversation with discussion of fieldwork methods, the role of the academy, and complicatios in fieldwork and public folklore programming.
      - Common Ground: Keith Enright interviewed by John Cash and Inta Carpenter, Tape 1, December 5, 1998 (Box 13)
        Keith Enright discusses his interest in preservation of Indiana Folklife, his heritage, and his thoughts on life and urban development in Bloomington. The interview focuses on his long-term public folklore project started with Dr. Warren Roberts on preserving and documenting the oldest pioneer homestead in Monroe County, the Mayfield Homestead. The property features a cave and architectural evidence of mystical symmetry perhaps influenced by Freemasonry.
      - Common Ground: Keith Enright interviewed by John Cash and Inta Carpenter, Tape 2, December 5, 1998 (Box 13)
        Conclusion of the interview with Keith Enright, discussing preservation and development in Bloomington, GIS mapping, historic photographs of architecture, and Habitat for Humanity projects.
    - Festival of American Folklife (FAF) (Box 7)
      - Case Studies, 1987 (Box 7)
      - Photos, 1987 (Box 7)
      - Presenters' Guide, 1987 (Box 7)
      - Research Guide, undated, circa 1987-1988 (Box 7)
      - Sawin Fieldwork Ms., 1988 (Box 7)
      - Transcript: Jean Reid, 1988 (Box 7)
    - Projects: Festival of American Folklife Responses to Report, 1987-1992 (Box 7)
    - Field School III Host Berea 43-264-20, 2003 (Box 7)
    - "Folklore and Community in Public Education" F404/804 Course, 1994 (Box 7)
    - Folklore and Education (Box 7)